zazzle.com 2017-06-29

# Zazzle Privacy Policy

Thanks for using <https://www.zazzle.com/> ("Site"). At Zazzle Inc. ("Zazzle"), we are committed to protecting your privacy. We have created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to make sure you know what information we collect and how we use it. By using the Site, you expressly consent to the collection, storage, disclosure and use of your information as we have outlined in this Privacy Policy and you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. 

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we make any changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you in accordance with our User Agreement. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. In addition, if we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information. We also encourage you to check back, from time to time, and review this Privacy Policy so that you always will know what personally identifiable information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it. Your continued use of the Site will be subject to the then current Privacy Policy. 

Zazzle has received TRUSTe's Privacy and Children's Privacy Seal, signifying that this Privacy Policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program, which is viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Site, <https://www.zazzle.com/> and other foreign language versions of the Site. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

**EU — U.S. Privacy Shield**

Zazzle, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Information about the Privacy Shield Framework can be found at the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List. <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

Zazzle, Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

Zazzle, Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission regarding personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our third party dispute resolution provider, JAMS. More information can be found [here](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). 

If JAMS does not resolve the matter, you may be able to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. For more information: [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint). 

**But first, a note about uploading and posting information on the Site:**

At the time you register for a Zazzle account, you will choose and provide us with an email address and password. When you upload a design, post a comment or message on the Site, provide information in connection with features such as fan clubs, wish lists, forums, member profiles, reviews and recommendation your user name may be visible to other users.

Additionally, if yours or your child's comment or message contains personally identifiable information and is posted by you in a page that is accessible to the public, third parties may make note of the information and you or your child may receive unsolicited messages from other parties as a result. Any content or information you upload that is visible to third parties may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. Always use care when you post such information.

**What information do we collect?** **Information provided by you:**

You may provide us with certain personally identifiable information when you: 

  * register for a Zazzle account;
  * order products or gift certificates;
  * request customer support or send us any other communication;
  * sign up for newsletters, email alerts, and special offers;
  * enter sweepstakes or contests;
  * sign up for, or redeem, special offers; 
  * respond to surveys; 
  * use our Email-to-a-Friend or Refer-A-Friend features; and
  * approve your child's request to open a Zazzle account in accordance with The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA).

Such information may include your name, email address, billing address, shipping address, and credit card number. You may also provide us with information about other people, such as their email addresses, if you email a product to a friend or refer a friend to the Site or our promotions. 

If you are under 13, we will collect your email address, password and age. Once you have selected "under 13," we will then ask for your parent's/guardians email address so that we may send them a notice and ask for their permission for you to use the Site. 

**Information collected by Cookies:**

Zazzle uses cookies on the Site to improve the quality of our Site and services to you. A cookie is a small text file on your computer which a website sends to your computer to allow the website to store information which uniquely identifies our users. Zazzle's cookies do not collect or store personally identifiable information. Rather, the cookie stores a token which uniquely identifies a particular user at a particular time. That token is then linked to the user information in our secured databases. You can always delete the cookies and reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to display a message when a cookie is being sent. If you reset your browser, some of the Site features and functionality may not be available to you and you may not be able to take advantage of all the features on the Site. 

We may work with other companies who place cookies or web beacons on our Site. We do not have access or control over these cookies. These companies help operate our websites and provide you with additional products and services. They are subject to confidentiality agreements with Zazzle and other legal restrictions. Zazzle does not permit any of these companies to collect personally identifiable information using cookies or web beacons on our websites. Certain functionalities related to the provision of additional products and services require marketers to share website usage information about visitors to the Site, who have received a targeted promotional campaign, with a reputable third-party advertising company for the purpose of targeting future campaigns and upgrading visitor information used in reporting statistics. To this end, Zazzle's third-party advertising company makes a note of some of the pages you visit on the Site through the use of pixel tags. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

**Information collected by Web Beacons and Log Files:**

Zazzle collects certain non-personally identifiable information through the use of web beacons and log files. Such information may include your IP address, browser type, Site usage, and whether you opened emails you received from us. 

**Information collected through Product Reviews:**

You may choose to submit a product review. If you post a review, we may ask for certain information to validate your review such as email address, photo, and your city/state/country of residence. If you submit a review, we may publish your geographic location or other anonymous information but your email address will be kept private. Additionally, any personally identifiable information that you submit as part of the review can be read or used by other visitors to the Site. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you choose to submit as part of your review. We believe you can post a helpful review without disclosing any personally identifiable information. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com). 

**How do we secure your information?**

When you place orders or access your account information, we use commercially reasonable and generally-accepted technological safeguards to secure any information we collect about you. The secure server software ("SSL") we use encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. In addition, your Zazzle account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. You should always take steps to protect the confidentiality of the password you select. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. 

We operate internationally and many of our computer systems are currently based in the United States. As a result, your personal data will be processed by us in the United States where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union. If you create a user account with us, you agree to this Privacy Policy and you consent to the transfer of all information you provide to us in the United States. 

You may also choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of our Site because such information may be required in order for you to: register as a member; purchase products or services; participate in a contest, promotion, survey, or sweepstakes; ask a question; or initiate other transactions on our Site. 

We work very hard to protect your privacy, but we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will always remain private. While we use industry-standard precautions to safeguard your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee complete security. If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com). 

**How do we use your information?**

We use the personally identifiable information you provide to: 

  * provide the features and functionality of the Site;
  * fulfill your requests for our products and services;
  * pay earnings;
  * communicate with you about the status of your orders and other inquiries about our products and services;
  * send you information about our products and services; 
  * for our internal business purposes, such as data analysis, audits and so forth; 
  * help us create content that is most relevant to you; and
  * provide notices about the results of sweepstakes, contest, and other promotions.

We use your email address to communicate with you about your account and to send you certain notification emails. You can change the frequency of those emails in your Zazzle account settings. 

When you purchase products from the Site, we may use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send marketing messages and notifications from time-to-time whether or not you created an account with us. You may unsubscribe or change the frequency of email notifications on the Account Settings page in "MyAccount." If you email a product to a friend or refer a friend to the Site or our promotions, we will use your friend's email to send them the e-mail you requested. Your friend's e-mail addresses will only be used for this purpose unless permission is otherwise granted. Zazzle does not store this information. Your friend may contact us at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

We use non-personally identifiable information to monitor the use and performance of the Site so that we can learn more about how people use the Site which helps us improve our products and services and significantly enhance your experience on our Site. 

**Does Zazzle disclose the information it collects to outside parties?**

We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties. Generally, Zazzle does not share personally identifiable information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies without your consent except that: 

Zazzle provides information to its agents and trusted service providers and contractors for limited purposes, such as fulfilling customer orders and processing credit card transactions; offering certain products and services; communicating with customers; providing customer service; managing information on our behalf; and enhancing the Site features and functionality. In such cases, we require that these parties agree to use the information solely for the purpose for which we provided it to them and in accordance with our Privacy Policy. 

If you sign up for a promotion (e.g., a contest or sweepstakes offer) or enroll in a service we offer in partnership with a third party, we may provide information (such as your name, email address, and account activity) to such third parties. 

Zazzle provides its sellers with the first name and city/state/country of residence of Zazzle customers who have purchased such seller's products. Zazzle may also release information (including your name, addresses, telephone number, and account activity) when we, in our sole discretion believe that such release is necessary or appropriate to: 

  * comply with law;
  * comply with subpoenas, warrants, court orders, government investigations, or other legal process;
  * enforce or apply the terms of any of our user or license agreements; 
  * investigate or respond to allegations of fraud, intellectual property infringement, or other unlawful activity
  * investigate fraud or similar claims; 
  * protect the rights, property or safety of Zazzle, our users, or others. 
  * to protect our operations; or
  * to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

Additionally, Zazzle releases certain information, including personally identifiable information, to report the sale of custom postage to the United States Postal Service ("USPS"). As part of our relationship with the USPS, we collect and may disclose information about purchasers of our Zazzle Custom Stamps products to the USPS at the request of USPS. To learn more about the USPS's privacy policy, please visit the [Privacy Policy](https://about.usps.com/who-we-are/privacy-policy/welcome.htm). 

In the event that Zazzle is acquired by or merges with another company, Zazzle reserves the right to transfer all information we have collected from our users, in connection with such acquisition or merger. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. 

Zazzle may disclose non-personally-identifiable information to third parties in aggregate form or to potential business partners and investors. 

Parents have the right to consent to the collection and use of their child's personal information without also consenting to the disclosure of such information to third parties, as we will not share your child's information with third parties. 

Zazzle will obtain assurances from its agents that they will only process the data for the limited and specified purposes consistent with the consent provided by the individual and will safeguard personal information consistently with this Policy. The assurance may include: a contract binding the agent to provide at least the same level of protection as is required by the relevant Privacy Shield Principles, being subject to EU Directive 95/46/EC (the EU Data Protection Directive), or Privacy Shield certification by the agent. 

**Advertising**

Zazzle may use third party service providers to place ads on our behalf across the internet and sometimes on the Site. They may collect anonymous information about yours or your child's visits to our Site, and yours or your child's interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about yours or your child's visits to this and other websites to target advertisements for goods and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a web beacon, which is industry standard technology used by most major sites. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this anonymous information about you or your child used by our third party service providers, please contact us at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com). You may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Parents may also opt their child out by contacting us at the email address listed above. 

Name of Third Party Partner | What info is shared with or collected by this partner | Partner's purpose | Link to Partner's privacy policy  
---|---|---|---  
Google Adservices | Anonymous order information, IP, and URL clickstream | Ad network | [google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Doubleclick | Anonymous order information, IP, and URL clickstream | Ad network | [.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google-analytics | Anonymous IP, URL clickstream related to viewing specific designer's products and stores. | Analytics | [.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Facebook | Anonymous order information, IP, and URL clickstream | Social/sharing tools | [.facebook.com/privacy/explanation](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)  
Criteo | Anonymous click stream and order information (Ad Views, Analytics, Browser Information, Hardware/Software Type, Interaction Data, Page Views), IP Address, Device ID  | Retargeting ads | [criteo.com/privacy](http://www.criteo.com/privacy)  
Omniture | Anonymous order information (Ad Views, Analytics, Browser Information, Hardware/Software Type, Interaction Data, Page Views), IP Address, Device ID | Analytics | [omniture.com/privacy](http://www.omniture.com/privacy)  
BlueHornet | Email (as provided to Zazzle by customers) and location information (by zip code) | Email marketing | [bluehornet.com/privacy](http://www.bluehornet.com/privacy)  
  
If you have any inquiries regarding our partner's privacy practices or how they use your child's personal information, please contact us directly at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com)

In addition, Zazzle is a dynamic marketplace with a great number of branded products and content. We will offer our users the opportunity to opt-in to receive from our partners emails, notifications of promotions and the like offered by such partners. You have the right to decline to opt-in to take advantage of this service. 

**Social Media Features and Widgets**

Our Site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, and widgets, such as the "ShareThis" button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Facebook Connect or other OpenID provider**

You can log in to our Site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

**Does this Privacy Policy apply when I access third party websites?**

You may be able to access third party websites directly from the Site. However, this Privacy Policy does not apply when you access third party websites. We cannot control how third parties may use personally identifiable information you disclose to them, so you should carefully review the privacy policy of any third party website you visit before using it or disclosing your personally identifiable information to its provider. 

**What about children's privacy?**

Children under the age of 13 are allowed to upload graphics and images and to order products on a parent's account. In addition, in order to generate custom postage, we must collect and record the following information: the date and time of the custom postage order, a unique order i.d., the amount of postage ordered in the transaction, and the zip code of the recipient of the custom postage. 

This information is used to: fulfill the requested order; confirm shipment; complete record keeping including royalty entitlements and other earnings, if any; allow users to comment on our blog or send messages; send monthly newsletters; allow users to upload a photo to their profile that may be publicly available to other users of the Site; report the sale of Zazzle Custom Stamps to the United States Postal Service, and advise the child concerning new Zazzle products, services or policies. If you no longer wish to allow your child to receive monthly newsletters, you or your child may login to your child's account and uncheck the box, alternatively you or your child may follow the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of each newsletter. 

Parents of children under the age of 13 have the option to consent to the collection of this information from their children or not. Such consent will not be used as consent for the dissemination of any of this information and the information will not be released by Zazzle to third parties without the parents' consent except as may be required by law or upon court order. Personally identifiable information at Zazzle is kept confidential and is disclosed only with the consent of the Zazzle user or as set forth in this Privacy Policy. We do not engage in the selling of information regarding the habits, behavior, buying patterns, or demographic information of our users. If you wish to review personal information that was collected from your child, have that personal information deleted or refuse further collection and use of that information, , you may send a request to Zazzle Customer Support. [Contact us](https://www.zazzle.com/about/ask) by sending an email with 'Parental Notification' in the subject line. Alternatively, you may contact the Zazzle Child Privacy Representative by phone, email, or letter at: 

Zazzle Inc.   
Attn: Privacy   
1800 Seaport Blvd  
Redwood City, CA 94063   
1(800)980-9890 

**How can I change, delete, or update my information?**

Most of your account information can be changed in the "MyAccount" section of the Site. If you have any questions about what information is stored or would like to obtain a copy of such information, please contact us at [privacy@zazzle.com](mailto:privacy@zazzle.com) or Privacy c/o Zazzle Inc., 1800 Seaport Blvd., Redwood City, CA 94063. After receiving proof of your identity, we will provide the information to you, and you may request that we delete or change any or all of the information. We will respond to your request to access within thirty (30) days. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

The current version of the Zazzle Privacy Policy was adopted effective as of September 29, 2016. 

  * Policies
